# Ronghua Xu, Ph.D.

☑ rxu22@binghamton.edu

https://scholar.google.com/citations?user=gKf0U28AAAAJ&hl=en

https://github.com/samuelxu999

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/ronghua-xu-bu/



# **Biographical Sketch**

#### About me

Ronghua Xu is an Assistant Professor of Applied Computing at Michigan Technological University. He earned a Ph.D. and an M.S. in Electrical and Computer Engineering at the Binghamton University - State University of New York (SUNY) in 2023 and 2018 respectively. He also received an M.S. in Mechanical and Electrical Engineering from Nanjing University of Aeronautics & Astronautics in 2010 and a B.S. in Mechanical Engineering from Nanjing University of Science & Technology, China in 2007. Before joining Binghamton University, he worked at Siemens on software development, system integration, and test automation from June 2010 to June 2016.

#### **Research Interests**

- ♦ Blockchain and Distributed Ledger Technology, Internet-of-Things (IoT), Machine Learning (ML), Cloud/Fog/Edge Computing Paradigm.
- ♦ Blockchain and smart contract enabled security solutions to Internet of Things (IoTs)
- ♦ Intelligence, assurance and resilience of next generation network.

## **Education**

Jun 2018 – Aug 2023 • Ph.D., Electrical and Computer Engineering, Binghamton University-SUNY,

Binghamton, NY, USA.

Dissertation title: A Secure-by-Design Federated Microchain Fabric for Internet-of-

Things(IoT) System
Advisor: Prof. Yu Chen

USA.

Thesis title: Capability Based Access Control Strategies to Deter DDoS Attacks Ex-

ploiting IoT Devices Advisor: Prof. Yu Chen

Sep 2007 – Mar 2010  $\diamond$  MS, Mechanical and Electrical Engineering, Nanjing University of Aeronau-

tics & Astronautics, Nanjing, China.

Thesis title: Research on Form-to-function Mapping and Re-creative Design Method

Based on Function Ontology Advisor: Prof. Dunbing Tang

Sep 2003 – Jul 2007  $\diamond$  **BS, Mechanical Engineering**, Nanjing University of Science & Technology, Nan-

jing, China.

# **Employment History**

Aug 2023 – Now Assistant Professor. Michigan Technological University, MI, USA.

Jun 2010 – Jun 2016 Software Engineer. Department of Software Development, Research & Devel-

opment Division, Siemens Numerical Control Ltd., Nanjing, China.

# **Teaching Experience**

Instructor  $\diamond$  Digital Forensics (SAT4816-5816), Fall 2023, 2023.

Teaching Assistant  $\Diamond$  Digital Logic Design (EECE-251), Fall 2018, 2019.

♦ Sophomore Design (EECE-287), Spring 2019, 2020.

♦ Computer Network Architecture (EECE-453/553), Fall 2018 - 2022.

♦ Network Security (EECE-658), Spring 2018 - 2019.

## **Skills**

Languages  $\diamond$  Strong reading, writing and speaking competencies for English, Mandarin Chinese.

Coding  $\diamond$  C/C++, Java, Python, C#, VB, tclsh, bash, powershell, sql, xml/xsl, LTEX, ...

Databases  $\diamond$  Mysql, Postgresql, sqlite.

Web Dev ♦ HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Flask Web Server.

Misc.  $\diamond$  Academic research, teaching, training, consultation.

## **Research Publications**

## **Journal Articles**

- Nagothu, D., **Xu**, **R.**, Chen, Y., Blasch, E., & Aved, A. (2022). Deterring deepfake attacks with an electrical network frequency fingerprints approach. *Future Internet*, 14(5), 125. Odoi:10.3390/fi14050125
- **Xu**, **R.**, & Chen, Y. (2022a).  $\mu$ Dfl: A secure microchained decentralized federated learning fabric atop iot networks. *IEEE Transactions on Network and Service Management*. 6 doi:10.1109/TNSM.2022.3179892
- Xu, R., Chen, Y., Chen, G., & Blasch, E. (2022). Sausa: Securing access, usage, and storage of 3d point cloud data by a blockchain-based authentication network. *Future Internet*, 14(12), 354. 60 doi:10.3390/fi14120354
- **Xu**, **R.**, Wei, S., Chen, Y., Chen, G., & Pham, K. (2022). Lightman: A lightweight microchained fabric for assurance-and resilience-oriented urban air mobility networks. *Drones*, *6*(12), 421. *Θ* doi:10.3390/drones6120421
- Qu, Q., Xu, R., Chen, Y., Blasch, E., & Aved, A. (2021). Enable fair proof-of-work (pow) consensus for blockchains in iot by miner twins (mint). *Future Internet*, 13(11), 291. Odoi:10.3390/fi13110291
- Xu, R., Nagothu, D., & Chen, Y. (2021b). Econledger: A proof-of-enf consensus based lightweight distributed ledger for iovt networks. *Future Internet*, 13(10), 248. Odi:10.3390/fi13100248

## **Conference Proceedings**

- Nagothu, D., **Xu**, **R.**, & Chen, Y. (2023). Dema: Decentralized electrical network frequency map for social media authentication. In *Disruptive technologies in information sciences vii* (Vol. 12542, pp. 57–72). SPIE.
- Qu, Q., Xu, R., Sun, H., Chen, Y., Sarkar, S., & Ray, I. (2023). A digital healthcare service architecture for seniors safety monitoring in metaverse. In 2023 ieee international conference on metaverse computing, networking and applications (metacom) (pp. 86–93). IEEE.
- Wei, S., Huang, H., Chen, G., Blasch, E., Chen, Y., **Xu**, **R.**, & Pham, K. (2023). Rodad: Resilience oriented decentralized anomaly detection for urban air mobility networks. In 2023 integrated communication, navigation and surveillance conference (icns) (pp. 1–11). IEEE.
- 5 **Xu**, **R.**, Chen, Y., Li, X., & Blasch, E. (2022). A secure dynamic edge resource federation architecture for cross-domain iot systems. In 2022 international conference on computer communications and networks (icccn) (pp. 1–7). IEEE. Odi:10.1109/ICCCN54977.2022.9868843
- Nagothu, D., Xu, R., Chen, Y., Blasch, E., & Aved, A. (2021a). Defake: Decentralized enf-consensus based deepfake detection in video conferencing. In 2021 ieee 23rd international workshop on multimedia signal processing (mmsp) (pp. 1–6). IEEE. Odo:10.1109/MMSP53017.2021.9733503
- Nagothu, D., Xu, R., Chen, Y., Blasch, E., & Aved, A. (2021b). Detecting compromised edge smart cameras using lightweight environmental fingerprint consensus. In *Proceedings of the 19th acm conference on embedded networked sensor systems* (pp. 505–510). ACM. 6 doi:10.1145/3485730.3493684
- 8 **Xu**, **R.**, & Chen, Y. (2021). Fed-ddm: A federated ledgers based framework for hierarchical decentralized data marketplaces. In 2021 international conference on computer communications and networks (icccn) (pp. 1–8). IEEE. Odo::10.1109/ICCCN52240.2021.9522359
- 9 Qu, Q., Xu, R., Nikouei, S. Y., & Chen, Y. (2020). An experimental study on microservices based edge computing platforms. In *leee infocom 2020-ieee conference on computer communications workshops* (infocom wkshps) (pp. 836–841). IEEE. doi:10.1109/INFOCOMWKSHPS50562.2020.9163068
- Xu, R., Chen, Y., Blasch, E., Aved, A., Chen, G., & Shen, D. (2020). Hybrid blockchain-enabled secure microservices fabric for decentralized multi-domain avionics systems. In *Sensors and systems for space applications xiii* (Vol. 11422, 114220J). International Society for Optics and Photonics. Optics and Photonics.
- Xu, R., Chen, Y., & Li, J. (2020). Poster: Microfl: A lightweight, secure-by-design edge network fabric for decentralized iot systems. In *The network and distributed system security symposium (ndss)*. Retrieved from https://www.ndss-symposium.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/NDSS2020posters\_paper\_19.pdf
- Xu, R., Zhai, Z., Chen, Y., & Lum, J. K. (2020). Bit: A blockchain integrated time banking system for community exchange economy. In 2020 ieee international smart cities conference (isc2) (pp. 1–8). IEEE. 60 doi:10.1109/ISC251055.2020.9239045
- Blasch, E., **Xu**, **R.**, Nikouei, S. Y., & Chen, Y. (2019). A study of lightweight dddas architecture for real-time public safety applications through hybrid simulation. In *2019 winter simulation conference* (wsc) (pp. 762–773). IEEE. doi:10.1109/WSC40007.2019.9004727
- Nikouei, S. Y., **Xu**, **R.**, Chen, Y., Aved, A., & Blasch, E. (2019). Decentralized smart surveillance through microservices platform. In *Sensors and systems for space applications xii* (Vol. 11017, 110170K). International Society for Optics and Photonics. Optics and Photonics. Optics and Photonics.

- **Xu**, **R.**, Chen, S., Yang, L., Chen, Y., & Chen, G. (2019). Decentralized autonomous imaging data processing using blockchain. In *Multimodal biomedical imaging xiv* (Vol. 10871, pp. 72−82). SPIE. **⊘** doi:10.1117/12. 2513243
- Xu, R., Nikouei, S. Y., Chen, Y., Blasch, E., & Aved, A. (2019). Blendmas: A blockchain-enabled decentralized microservices architecture for smart public safety. In 2019 ieee international conference on blockchain (blockchain) (pp. 564–571). IEEE. Odi:10.1109/Blockchain.2019.00082
- Nagothu, D., **Xu**, **R.**, Nikouei, S. Y., & Chen, Y. (2018). A microservice-enabled architecture for smart surveillance using blockchain technology. In 2018 ieee international smart cities conference (isc2) (pp. 1–4). IEEE. 60 doi:10.1109/ISC2.2018.8656968
- Nikouei, S. Y., Chen, Y., Song, S., **Xu**, **R.**, Choi, B.-Y., & Faughnan, T. (2018). Smart surveillance as an edge network service: From harr-cascade, svm to a lightweight cnn. In 2018 ieee 4th international conference on collaboration and internet computing (cic) (pp. 256–265). IEEE. Odi:10.1109/CIC.2018.00042
- Nikouei, S. Y., Chen, Y., Song, S., **Xu**, **R.**, Choi, B.-Y., & Faughnan, T. R. (2018). Real-time human detection as an edge service enabled by a lightweight cnn. In *2018 ieee international conference on edge computing* (*edge*) (pp. 125–129). IEEE. doi:10.1109/EDGE.2018.00025
- Nikouei, S. Y., Xu, R., Nagothu, D., Chen, Y., Aved, A., & Blasch, E. (2018). Real-time index authentication for event-oriented surveillance video query using blockchain. In 2018 ieee international smart cities conference (isc2) (pp. 1–8). IEEE. 6 doi:10.1109/ISC2.2018.8656668
- Xu, R., Chen, Y., Blasch, E., & Chen, G. (2018a). A federated capability-based access control mechanism for internet of things (iots). In *Sensors and systems for space applications xi* (Vol. 10641, 106410U). International Society for Optics and Photonics. 6 doi:10.1117/12.2305619
- Xu, R., Chen, Y., Blasch, E., & Chen, G. (2018b). Blendcac: A blockchain-enabled decentralized capability-based access control for iots. In 2018 ieee international conference on internet of things (ithings) and ieee green computing and communications (greencom) and ieee cyber, physical and social computing (cpscom) and ieee smart data (smartdata) (pp. 1027–1034). IEEE. Odoi:10.1109/Cybermatics\_2018.2018.00191
- Xu, R., Lin, X., Dong, Q., & Chen, Y. (2018). Constructing trustworthy and safe communities on a blockchainenabled social credits system. In *Proceedings of the 15th eai international conference on mobile and ubiquitous* systems: Computing, networking and services (pp. 449–453). 6 doi:10.1145/3286978.3287022
- Xu, R., Nikouei, S. Y., Chen, Y., Polunchenko, A., Song, S., Deng, C., & Faughnan, T. R. (2018). Real-time human objects tracking for smart surveillance at the edge. In 2018 ieee international conference on communications (icc) (pp. 1–6). IEEE. Odoi:10.1109/ICC.2018.8422970

## **Book Chapters**

- Xu, R., Nagothu, D., & Chen, Y. (2023). Ecom: Epoch randomness-based consensus committee configuration for iot blockchains. In *Principles and practice of blockchains* (pp. 135–154). Odoi:10.1007/978-3-031-10507-4\_7
- **Xu**, **R.**, Chen, Y., & Blasch, E. (2021). Microchain: A light hierarchical consensus protocol for iot systems. In *Blockchain applications in iot ecosystem* (pp. 129–149). Springer.
- Nagothu, D., **Xu**, **R.**, Nikouei, S. Y., Zhao, X., & Chen, Y. (2020). Smart surveillance for public safety enabled by edge computing. In *Edge computing: Models, technologies and applications* (pp. 409–433). doi:10.1049/PBPC033E\_ch19
- **Xu, R.,** Chen, Y., & Blasch, E. (2020). Decentralized access control for iot based on blockchain and smart contract. In *Modeling and design of secure internet of things* (pp. 505–528). Odoi:10.1002/9781119593386. ch22

Nikouei, S. Y., **Xu**, **R.**, & Chen, Y. (2019). Smart surveillance video stream processing at the edge for real-time human objects tracking. In *Fog and edge computing: Principles and paradigms* (pp. 319–346). Odoi:10.1002/9781119525080.ch13

#### **Books**

Xu, R., Chen, Y., & Blasch, E. (2023). Lightweight blockchain for internet of things: Rationale and a case study. Bellingham, Washington 98227-0010 USA: SPIE Press.

## **Professional Services**

## Conference Technical Program Committee (TPC)

- ♦ The 6th IFIP International Internet of Things (IoT) Conference (IFIP-IoT 2023)
- The 2023 EAI International Conference on Security and Privacy in Cyber-Physical Systems and Smart Vehicles (SmartSP 2023)
- ♦ Artificial Intelligence and Machine Learning Technologies for IoT (AMT) (IEEE WiMob-SPPDT'2023).
- ♦ The 6rd International Workshop on BLockchain Enabled Sustainable Smart Cities (BLESS 2023) (in conjunction with ICCCN 2023 Conference).
- ♦ The 5rd IEEE International Conference on Blockchain (Blockchain-2022).
- ♦ The 5rd International Workshop on BLockchain Enabled Sustainable Smart Cities (BLESS 2022) (in conjunction with ICCCN 2022 Conference).
- ♦ WiMob Short Papers, Posters and Demos Track (IEEE WiMob-SPPDT'2022).
- ♦ The 4rd IEEE International Conference on Blockchain (Blockchain-2021).
- ♦ The 4rd International Workshop on BLockchain Enabled Sustainable Smart Cities (BLESS 2021) (in conjunction with ICCCN 2021 Conference).
- ♦ The 3rd IEEE International Conference on Blockchain (Blockchain-2020).
- The 3rd International Workshop on BLockchain Enabled Sustainable Smart Cities (BLESS 2020) (in conjunction with ISC2 2020 Conference).
- The 2rd International Workshop on BLockchain Enabled Sustainable Smart Cities (BLESS 2019) (in conjunction with ISC2 2019 Conference).
- ♦ The 1st International Workshop on Lightweight Blockchain for Edge Intelligence and Security (LightChain 2019).

## **Reviewer for Journals**

- Elsevier Computer Communications
- Elsevier Computer Networks
- Elsevier Computers & Security
- Elsevier Pervasive and Mobile Computing
- ♦ Elsevier Blockchain: Research and Applications
- ♦ Elsevier Sustainable Cities and Society
- Elsevier International Journal of Intelligent Networks
- ♦ IEEE Access
- ♦ IEEE Internet-of-Things Journal (IoT-J)
- ♦ IEEE Transactions on Big Data (TBD)
- ♦ IEEE Transactions on Industrial Informatics (TII)
- ♦ IEEE Transactions on Dependable and Secure Computing (TDSC)
- ♦ IEEE Transactions on Network Science and Engineering (TNSE)

# **Professional Services (continued)**

- MDPI Applied Sciences
- MDPI Sensor and Actuator Networks
- Hindawi Wireless Communications and Mobile Computing

## **Reviewer for Conferences**

- ♦ IEEE International Conference on Computer Communications (INFOCOM)
- ♦ IEEE International Conference on Blockchain (Blockchain)
- ♦ IEEE Global Communications Conference (GLOBECOM)
- ♦ IEEE International Conference on Wireless and Mobile Computing, Networking And Communications (WiMob)
- ♦ IEEE International Performance Computing and Communications Conference (IPCCC)
- ♦ IEEE International Conference on Consumer Electronics (ICCE)
- ♦ IEEE International Conference on Communications (ICC)
- ♦ IEEE International Smart Cities Conference (ISC2)
- ♦ IEEE International Conference on Cloud Networking (CloudNet)
- ♦ ACM Conference on Embedded Networked Sensor Systems (SenSys)
- ♦ EAI SECURECOMM

# **Miscellaneous Experience**

### **Awards and Achievements**

- 2019 **2019 Computers Best Paper Award**, Multidisciplinary Digital Publishing Institute (MDPI).
- outstanding MS Research, Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering, Binghamton University.

## On campus Services

 Fall 2018 Leadership Volunteers, International Student and Scholar Services (ISSS), Binghamton University.

## **Membership**

- ♦ IEEE
- ♦ ACM